<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- 
cached data at 17:14:03
cached id 76aaeee55f1a2cd366a5162c3f82fb79
-->
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
    xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
    <channel>
        <atom:link
            href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/feeds/rss/incidents/"
            rel="self"
            type="application/rss+xml" />
        <title>InciWeb National Incidents</title>
        <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov</link>
        <description>Latest incident updates nationally</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 17:14:03 -05:00</pubDate>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <item>
            <title>Snow Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 17:11:16 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 17:11:16 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>47.703333333333 -113.4</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>47.703333333333</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-113.4</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6497/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6497/</guid>
            <description>Although still creeping and smoldering, minimal fire activity occurred
                throughout the weekend and into Tuesday, August 13th, due to an increase in RH
                values, lower temperatures, and significant precipitation; the Black Bear
                Administrative site has received 0.61&quot; of rain while the Salmon Forks
                Administration site has received 0.81&quot;. Fire behavior is expected to pick back
                up with warmer, drier weather conditions predicted for the area over the next few
                days. Notably, the fire has not yet established in the area burned by both the 2000
                Helen Creek Fire and the 2013 Damnation Fire. The fire is burning the heavy dead and
                down fuels in the 2000 burn area and along the grassy slope west of the 2013 burn,
                but has not spread into the twice burned area despite hot, dry conditions and
                significant growth elsewhere. Continued low to moderate surface fire and growth
                through the heavy dead and down fuels in the 2000 fire area will continue due to the
                low 1000hr fuel moisture. Spotted Bear and Hungry...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Williams Flats Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 17:00:48 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 17:00:48 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>47.98 -118.62388888889</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>47.98</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-118.62388888889</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6493/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6493/</guid>
            <description>Keller, WA- The Williams Flats Fire started on August 2, 2019 after a band
                of early morning thunderstorms with lightning moved across the eastern portion of
                the Colville Indian Reservation. The fire is burning south of Silver Creek
                Road,within the designated Game Reserve. Roads have been closed to this area at
                Kuehne Road and Canteen Creek Roads and plus other roads which could access the fire
                area. This is for firefighter and public safety. The fire is moving east and has
                crossed crossed Brody Creek Road and Redford Canyon.Steep slopes, limited access and
                primitive roads conditions are hampering containment efforts.Colville Tribal Natural
                Resource Law Enforcement Officers are asking boaters to stay clear of the
                firefighting efforts at Lake Roosevelt Recreational Area.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Trumbull (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 16:09:32 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 16:09:32 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.411944444444 -113.14083333333</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.411944444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-113.14083333333</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6514/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6514/</guid>
            <description>News Release BLM Arizona Strip District, Arizona For Immediate Release:
                August 14, 2019Media Contact: Rachel T. Carnahan, Public Affairs Officer
                rcarnahan@blm.gov (435) 688-3303 Trumbull Fire update and notice of temporary fire
                area closureSt. George, Utah – On August 5, 2019, fire managers responded to a
                lightning caused fire located approximately 53 miles south of St. George, Utah
                within the Grand Canyon-Parashant National Monument. The “Trumbull Fire,” located in
                the Mt. Trumbull Wilderness is now approximately 505 acres, burning in ponderosa
                pine, oak brush, pine needle duff and grass. Multiple resources from the Bureau of
                Land Management (BLM), Arizona Strip District are monitoring the fire; including one
                helicopter, one engine, and a fire effects monitor. This lightning caused fire is
                being monitored as it burns naturally across the landscape. This fire is being
                allowed to play its natural role within the fire-adapted Ponderosa pine ecosystem.
                Under the right...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Wood Canyon (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 15:56:19 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 15:56:19 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>39.740555555556 -118.1975</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>39.740555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-118.1975</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6520/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6520/</guid>
            <description>8-15-19 update, Wood Canyon Fire air and ground fire fighting units are
                engaged in suppression activities. Corrections to mapping projections have the
                fire's size at 1,383 acres. The fire is burning in Pinon Juniper with sage and grass
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Red Feather Prescribed Burn (Prescribed Fire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 15:04:47 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 15:04:47 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>40.852222222222 -105.57555555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>40.852222222222</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-105.57555555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5027/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5027/</guid>
            <description>August 15 Update: Conditions look good for ignition of the Red Feather
                Prescribed Burn on August 16. Expect to see firefighters and smoke in the area
                Friday. If conditions allow, burning could continue over the weekend. Canyon Lake
                Ranger District fire and fuel managers are monitoring conditions in the Roosevelt
                National Forest to return to operations on the Red Feather Prescribed Burn as soon
                as Thursday, June 27. If conditions allow, burning could continue throughout the
                weekend and into next week.This prescribed burn is located north of Red Feather
                Lakes, Colo., east of the Crystal Lakes Subdivision at 8,500 feet elevation. A great
                deal of work has already taken place on this burn and provides a treated line or
                previously burned ground around much of the perimeter. Firefighters plan to burn
                approximately 300 acres of unburned ground, as well as reenter some areas that were
                burned previously. In some of those previously burned areas, the burn was conducted
                when there was higher fuel...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Park Ridge Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:58:47 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:58:47 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>38.090555555556 -111.32527777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>38.090555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.32527777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6486/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6486/</guid>
            <description>On the evening of July 24, 2019, a lightning strike ignited a single tree
                in the Park Ridge area of Boulder Mountain. Fremont River Ranger District plans to
                manage this ignition to aid towards a healthy Ponderosa pine ecosystem, by utilizing
                low intensity under burn
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pemberton Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:41:55 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:41:55 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>34.718333333333 -112.68027777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>34.718333333333</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-112.68027777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6521/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6521/</guid>
            <description>The Pemberton Fire is a lightning caused wildfire that is being used to
                reduce hazardous fuel build up and improve ecosystem
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Sheridan Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:40:10 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:40:10 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>34.677777777778 -112.89027777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>34.677777777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-112.89027777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6522/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6522/</guid>
            <description>The Sheridan Fire is a lightning-caused wildfire that is being used to
                improve resource conditions in the area.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>SHF Lightning Fires 2019 (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:56:15 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:56:15 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>41.063333333333 -122.63805555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>41.063333333333</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-122.63805555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6370/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6370/</guid>
            <description>Lightning storms moving through the area have ignited several small fires.
                Forest officials and firefighters closely monitor these storms and use a combination
                of aerial reconnaissance flights, fire engines patrols, and reports of fire activity
                from the public in order to respond quickly and determine potential growth activity
                of the fires and develop appropriate response activity. Reconnaissance flights are
                part of our normal operating plan after lightning storms.Below we have listed each
                fire by the time the fire was reported, the name given to the fire, the approximate
                location and estimated fire size (if known) and current status. Any large fires will
                have a new &quot;incident&quot; page started in InciWeb. South Fork Management Unit
                (Hayfork and Platina area) 08/09/2019 19:56, PINE, W of Brushy Mtn, 0.25, acre, Out
                Trinity River Management Unit (Weaverville, Big Bar, Trinity Lake, Trinity Alps)
                08/10/2019 19:11, MONTGOMERY, Montgomery Ridge near Hwy 3 0.1 acre, Out 08/10/2019
                07:21,...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Springs Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:54:03 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:54:03 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>37.825833333333 -118.87222222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>37.825833333333</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-118.87222222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6477/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6477/</guid>
            <description>Springs Fire Update 8-15-19 Current Situation: The Springs Fire is being
                managed with a strategy to reintroduce fire into the landscape in its’ natural role.
                Overnight firefighters continued to prep and strategically apply fire to the
                landscape to further secure the fire to containment lines. Last night an Unmanned
                Aircraft System (UAS), commonly referred to as a drone was used in firing
                operations. Smoke is expected to be variable and depends on the daily winds. From
                evening into early morning smoke may drain into the Long Valley area, potentially
                impacting the community of Crowley Lake. As winds shift late morning into early
                afternoon the smoke will begin dispersing towards Mammoth Lakes, Devils Postpile,
                June Lake, and Lee Vining. Benton may expect lighter smoke later in the afternoons
                as winds are expected to shift out of the southwest. The latest daily air quality
                forecasts and site by site details can be found at-
                https://fires.airfire.org/outlooks/InyoNationalForest The...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Frehner Canyon (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:38:34 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:38:34 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.821388888889 -113.88416666667</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.821388888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-113.88416666667</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6512/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6512/</guid>
            <description>August 15 update: The Frehner Canyon Fire is 100% contained and in patrol
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Main Street (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:37:30 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:37:30 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.741666666667 -113.48694444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.741666666667</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-113.48694444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6513/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6513/</guid>
            <description>August 15 update: Main Street Fire is 100% contained and in patrol
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hurricane Cliffs Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:36:13 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:36:13 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.585277777778 -113.29611111111</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.585277777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-113.29611111111</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6472/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6472/</guid>
            <description>Update August 15, 2019. The fire is contained and</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cove Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:17:44 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 13:17:44 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>45.328055555556 -114.45277777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>45.328055555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-114.45277777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6495/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6495/</guid>
            <description>Crews continue to patrol and mop-up the fire’s edge and clean-up
                equipment.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Saber Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 12:57:11 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 12:57:11 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>35.010555555556 -111.90138888889</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>35.010555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.90138888889</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6519/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6519/</guid>
            <description>The lightning-caused Saber Fire was reported by Turkey Butte Lookout on
                Aug. 2, 2019 and has grown to 95 acres. The fire is located 1.5 miles south of
                Turkey Butte Lookout and 12 miles northwest of Sedona. Fire managers on the Coconino
                National Forest have determined that the fire will benefit the ecosystem as it moves
                across the landscape naturally consuming dense forest fuels.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ikes Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 12:49:41 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 12:49:41 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.348611111111 -112.28527777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.348611111111</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-112.28527777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6475/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6475/</guid>
            <description>Wildland Fire in Grand Canyon National Park: The lightning-caused fire is
                being utilized to fulfill its natural role in a fire-dependent ecosystem within a
                defined planning area of 8,000 acres on the Kaibab Plateau. The fire is being
                utilized to achieve a variety of resource objectives including reducing hazardous
                fuels, promoting forest regeneration, improving wildlife habitat, and restoring more
                open forest understory with grasses and forbs. Each fire start within the National
                Park is evaluated by fire management officials for the most appropriate management
                strategy. Firefighter safety, resources at risk, location of the fire, available
                resources, regional and national preparedness levels, and weather forecast are taken
                into consideration when responding to a wildfire ignition. Location and Cause: The
                Ikes Fire, which started on July 25, is a lighting caused fire located approximately
                three miles east of Swamp Point in Grand Canyon National Park North Rim.Current
                Conditions:...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Crab Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 12:37:10 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 12:37:10 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>46.501388888889 -114.57444444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>46.501388888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-114.57444444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6467/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6467/</guid>
            <description>The Lochsa-Powell Ranger District of the Nez Perce-Clearwater National
                Forests is managing the lightning-caused Crab Fire as a full-suppression fire.
                Reported at 10:25 on July 26, the fire is located approximately 6 miles east of the
                Powell Ranger Station. The fire does not pose a near term risk to communities.
                Currently, the only values immediately threatened by the fire are timber values.
                After closely evaluating excellent efforts by the responding smokejumpers and
                aircraft, and considering the probability for success of the long-term work required
                to fully extinguish this fire, the decision was made on Saturday, July 27th, to
                disengage from direct suppression tactics on the fire. Fire managers decided to
                implement indirect suppression tactics using trails and roads and natural features
                such as ridges and streams as fire lines. Heavy equipment was brought in to
                reinforce these strategic lines. This will limit exposure and risk to firefighters
                and will provide a high probability of...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rawhide Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 11:39:58 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 11:39:58 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>32.321388888889 -104.78555555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>32.321388888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-104.78555555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6518/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6518/</guid>
            <description>The lightning-caused Rawhide Fire on the Guadalupe Ranger District of the
                Lincoln National Forest has been allowed to grow to 2500 acres within the
                21,500-acre planning area to fulfill its essential role of reducing forest fuels and
                improve overall ecosystem health. Favorable conditions, including light winds and
                precipitation in areas adjacent to the fire, have resulted in a low-intensity fire
                that is moving along the forest floor. The Rawhide Fire started near Rawhide Canyon
                about five miles northwest of Sitting Bull Falls and is burning in mostly grass,
                shrubs and some juniper trees. Burnout operations are planned, as conditions allow,
                over the next three days, which may result in smoke being visible from Carlsbad and
                Queen, NM.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Castle Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 11:24:38 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 11:24:38 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.531111111111 -112.22805555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.531111111111</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-112.22805555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6439/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6439/</guid>
            <description>The Kaibab National Forest plans to allow the lightning-caused Castle Fire
                to continue growing within a defined area in order to fulfill its natural role of
                reducing dense forest fuels and improving overall ecosystem health. Patrolling and
                monitoring the fire as well as removing hazard trees is the current plan.The
                wildfire, which was discovered July 12, is located about 11 miles south of Jacob
                Lake, 3 miles west of Highway 67, and just east of Forest Road 761 near Oquer Canyon
                on the North Kaibab Ranger District of the Kaibab National Forest. The Castle Fire
                is burning in an area with dense mixed conifer, heavy fuel loading, and a
                significant amount of dead and down trees. Allowing the fire to act as a natural
                disturbance process in the ecosystem will help meet a variety of resource objectives
                including restoring the forest structure to more historic conditions, reducing
                spruce and fir encroachment of area meadows, removing fuels that could feed future
                severe wildfires, and...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Beeskove Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:56:28 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:56:28 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>46.962222222222 -113.8675</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>46.962222222222</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-113.8675</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6458/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6458/</guid>
            <description>The lightning-caused Beeskove Fire was detected on Tuesday morning, July
                23, 2019. The fire is burning in a remote location five miles northeast of the main
                Rattlesnake Trailhead within the Rattlesnake National Recreation Area. The terrain
                is interspersed with steep rocky slopes, rugged terrain and forested areas absent of
                a past fire history so the forest floor is laden with downed and dead fuels.
                Firefighters are attacking this fire under a full suppression strategy utilizing
                indirect tactics due to inaccessibility and high-risk conditions. Indirect control
                lines are under construction in order to protect surrounding communities and other
                values at risk. Management of the fire is under Joe Sampson’s Type 2 Incident
                Management Team. Missoula County, will you get emergency alerts when you need them?
                Missoula County Office of Emergency Management uses Smart911 to inform citizens of
                emergency alerts including fires, missing children, evacuations and more. For more
                informaton please...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Poison Canyon Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:47:53 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:47:53 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>37.834444444444 -109.79944444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>37.834444444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-109.79944444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6471/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6471/</guid>
            <description>Lightning caused fire 23 miles west of Monticello, Utah on the Monticello
                District of the Manti-La Sal National Forest. Fire is burning on a mesa top in
                Ponderosa Pine litter and dead and down fuels. Aspen, oak brush and grass are
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Peavine Canyon Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:46:12 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:46:12 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>37.723333333333 -109.85722222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>37.723333333333</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-109.85722222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6452/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6452/</guid>
            <description>Discovery: July 16 1720 hoursCause: Lightning Initial Size reported: 3
                acresLocation: 22 miles west of Blanding, UT in Peavine Canyon in the Dark Canyon
                Wilderness area of the Manti-La Sal NFBurning in subalpine fire and ponderosa with
                an understory of manzanita and oak brush. Occasional group and single tree torching.
                Creeping and smoldering in ground fuel.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Chippean Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:44:43 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:44:43 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>37.831111111111 -109.65</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>37.831111111111</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-109.65</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6510/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6510/</guid>
            <description>Lightning caused fire 16 miles northwest of Blanding, Utah on the
                Monticello Ranger District of the Manti-La Sal National Forest. Fire is burning in
                steep terrain with ponderosa pine litter and understory with manzanita brush
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ward Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:29:21 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:29:21 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>42.0325 -122.17527777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>42.0325</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-122.17527777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6516/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6516/</guid>
            <description>The Ward Fire started early afternoon August 9th, 2019 when a lightning
                storm came through the area. The fire instantly started running and spotting, aided
                by topography and winds. Crews from ODF and BLM along with Green Diamond timber
                company responded rapidly. Due to the favorable weather and quick action on the part
                of the cooperators good progress is being made. Cooperators include Klamath-Lake
                Distirct - Oregon Department of Forestry, Klamath Falls Resource Area, Lakeview
                District BLM, Green Diamond Resource Company and Klamath County Fire
                DepartmentOregon Department of Forestry Type 1 IMT 2 (Chris Cline, Incident
                Commander) assumed command at 6pm August 10,
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Horsefly Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:04:22 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:04:22 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>46.963055555556 -112.44083333333</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>46.963055555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-112.44083333333</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6502/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6502/</guid>
            <description>Shane Martin's Central Montana Type 3 Incident Management Team assumed
                command of the Horsefly Fire at 6:00 a.m. on Tuesday, August 13,
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Boulin Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 09:57:50 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 09:57:50 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>35.392777777778 -112.01083333333</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>35.392777777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-112.01083333333</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6511/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6511/</guid>
            <description>The Boulin Fire, discovered on August 6, was caused by lightning and has
                grown to approximately 1155 acres. It is located near the junction of forest roads
                141 and 713 approximately 9 miles north of Interstate 40 at the northwest corner of
                Spring Valley.Managers will use multiple strategies that will ultimately contain
                this fire within a defined planning area of approximately 4200 acres. Fire will be
                allowed to move towards designated roads that serve as safe and effective control
                features. Fire activity may fluctuate periodically as daily weather conditions
                influence fire behavior and spread. Operations have been successful in meeting
                multiple objectives and all containment lines are holding with no control problems
                occurring. Fire behavior continues to burn with a low to moderate intensity backing
                through grasses and ponderosa pine litter consuming dead and down fuels. Crews
                periodically ignite the edges of the containment lines to stay aligned with the
                fires natural...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nethker Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 09:11:04 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 09:11:04 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>45.245555555556 -115.93</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>45.245555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-115.93</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6496/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6496/</guid>
            <description>UPDATE, August 15, 2019: The Nethker Fire is now 68 percent contained as
                crews continue to make progress in the northern area of the fire.Some islands of
                previously unburned vegetation inside the fire perimeter burned yesterday, leading
                to a small increase in the size of the fire to 2,351 acres. The Warren Wagon Road is
                open to the public, however, the French Creek/Burgdorf Road remains closed. With
                increased weekend traffic, please drive with caution. Firefighters and their
                vehicles will be working in the area. Smoke will be visible along the road and
                within the interior of containment lines. These areas have been secured and
                firefighters will continue to extinguish them. Firefighters have moved into the
                mop-up stages of securing the fireline on the southern end of the Nethker Fire,
                looking for hot spots and putting them out. Part of this work will also include
                repairing suppression lines to help mitigate the impact of firefighting efforts. The
                Nethker Fire was started by lightning...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Shady Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 08:30:22 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 08:30:22 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>44.516944444444 -115.01888888889</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>44.516944444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-115.01888888889</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6433/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6433/</guid>
            <description>Fire activity is minimal at this time.The lightning caused Shady Fire was
                reported the evening of July 10. The fire is located approximately two (2) miles
                east of Seafoam Guard Station in the Frank Church River of No Return Wilderness on
                the Middle Fork Ranger District. Due to heavy fuel loading, active fire behavior,
                and the presence of numerous snags, firefighters have been unable to directly engage
                the fire. The Shady Fire is being managed with a point protection strategy (a
                wildfire response strategy, which protects specific assets or highly valued
                resources from the wildfire without directly halting the continued spread of the
                wildfire) to minimize exposure to fire personnel while protecting identified values.
                The strategy takes in to account exposure to firefighters, values at risk, impacts
                to area user groups, and wilderness values. Firefighters are monitoring fire
                progression towards values, with the priority of fire mangers being to provide for
                firefighter and public safety...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Devore Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 17:32:27 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 17:32:27 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>48.258055555556 -120.71555555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>48.258055555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-120.71555555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6463/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6463/</guid>
            <description>Lightning-Ignited Fire Burning in the Wilderness This Devore Creek Fire is
                burning entirely within the Glacier Peak Wilderness, between 5,700 – 6,800 feet of
                elevation. Lightning storms came through the area on July 23 and 24, 2019. The fire
                was reported on July 26 and first observed at by aerial reconnaissance at five
                acres. Rapellers arrived within two hours of the initial report and the fire had
                grown to approximately 75 acres. They could not safety engage the fire directly due
                to its size, the extremely steep terrain, and the amount of fuel available to burn.
                Fire Expected to Burn Until a Season Ending Weather Event The fire has seen minimal
                growth in recent days, but due to the fire’s remote location and the heavy fuels
                it’s burning in, the fire will be on the landscape for the rest of the season. Days
                are getting shorter and the chances of active fire growth are diminishing but the
                fire could come back to life with an extended warming and drying trend. There may
                still be...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hess Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 17:28:09 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 17:28:09 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>65.699166666667 -148.35916666667</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>65.699166666667</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-148.35916666667</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6404/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6404/</guid>
            <description>The Hess Creek Fire started June 21, 2019 by lightning moving through the
                area. It quickly spread through the dry black spruce. Total acreage as of July 30
                was 189,369 acres.A complete demobilization of personnel and equipment from the fire
                occurred on Aug. 9. The fire will be monitored through the rest of the season.
                Minimal fire growth is expected but remains possible if warm and dry weather
                returns. If this occurs, some activity and smoke may be visible around mile 61-62 of
                the Elliott Highway. However, this activity will likely not impact the highway or be
                much of a concern. The fire burned underground in many areas of the tundra, into
                deep duff and through tree root systems. Fire weakened trees can fall with very
                little wind. White ash on the ground may indicate deep pockets of hot ash where
                roots and ground vegetation have burned and may continue to burn below ground level.
                Severe burns may occur by stepping or falling into these pockets of hot ash. Walking
                through burned areas...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2019 Umatilla NF Prescribed Fire (Prescribed Fire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 16:17:10 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 16:17:10 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>45.67 -118.87</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>45.67</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-118.87</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5808/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5808/</guid>
            <description>The Umatilla National Forest prescribed fire page contains information on
                the Forest's planned, active and completed prescribed burning for 2019. In general,
                there are two burn seasons each year to accomplish prescribed fire projects. Early
                season burns typically occur in late winter through the early fire season in late
                spring/early summer. Late season burns typically occur in late fire season and into
                December. The specific dates of a burn during a season is dependent on many
                variables including wildfire activity, resource availability, current and predicted
                weather, and smoke management constraints. Frequent, low-intensity fire is essential
                for healthy forests and reducing the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire caused by
                excessive fuel buildup. Prescribed burning is an effective tool for removing
                excessive amounts of brush, shrubs, and trees, while also encouraging the growth of
                native vegetation. NEW! Prescribed Fire Activity Interactive Map (This interactive
                map will be best...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dixon Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 15:48:10 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 15:48:10 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>38.566666666667 -119.73916666667</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>38.566666666667</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-119.73916666667</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6474/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6474/</guid>
            <description>Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest fire managers are making use of a
                lightning-caused fire to meet multiple resource objectives in the Carson-Iceberg
                Wilderness. The Dixon Fire is located east of Silver Peak on the north side of Dixon
                Creek and was discovered on July 28 by aerial reconnaissance after storms passed
                through the area. Fire is a natural occurring component of Sierra Nevada ecosystems,
                important for both plants and animals. The reason for managing a naturally-occurring
                wildfire is to allow fire to play its historical role on the landscape. A naturally
                ignited fire can decrease the threat of future high intensity, high-severity
                wildfires by reducing hazardous fuel accumulations; reduce the risk of insect and
                disease outbreak; recycle nutrients that increase soil productivity; and improve
                wildlife habitat by increasing forbs/forage.The nine-acre Dixon Fire is burning deep
                in the Wilderness and being managed for the following multiple resource objectives:
                reducing accumulated...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Chalkyitsik Complex (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 14:51:12 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 14:51:12 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>66.545555555556 -143.05944444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>66.545555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-143.05944444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6494/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6494/</guid>
            <description>General Summary of the Chalkyitsik Complex Incident In mid-July storms
                passed through the Yukon Flats with thousands of lightning strikes. Drought
                conditions left the trees and duff layer very dry allowing fires to grow and
                difficult to contain. The rest of Alaska was also experiencing an extreme fire
                season and resources were limited. The BLM Alaska Fire Service (AFS) requested the
                assistance of the Alaska Interagency Incident Management Teams to oversee fires
                burning east of Chalkyitsik and west of Fort Yukon. The highest priority for fire
                personnel was to ensure the protection of the Gwich’in village of Chalkyitsik.
                Resources such as equipment and personnel have completed their missions and have
                been transported to Fairbanks for release to their home units. Fire managers have
                built a plan to support a proactive response should fire activity increase in the
                weeks and months ahead. The BLM AFS will regularly conduct reconnaissance flights to
                monitor fire activity and possible...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Milepost 97 Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 13:30:37 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 13:30:37 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>42.913055555556 -123.2675</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>42.913055555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-123.2675</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6461/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6461/</guid>
            <description>The Milepost 97 fire, located about 1 mile southeast of Canyonville was
                reported Wednesday, July 24th at approximately 10:00 p.m. The fire is burning in
                steep, rocky terrain with limited access. Currently, the Milepost 97 Fire is burning
                in an old fire scar that originally burned in 1987. The Oregon Department of
                Forestry Incident Management Team #3 (IC Smith) has been assigned to the fire to
                assist the Douglas Forest Protective Association with fire suppression
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nevada Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 11:16:32 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 11:16:32 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>46.827222222222 -112.56666666667</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>46.827222222222</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-112.56666666667</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6484/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6484/</guid>
            <description>Mike Almas's Northern Rockies Incident Management Team 3 assumed command of
                the Nevada Creek Fire at 6:00 p.m. on Friday, August 3, 2019. The Nevada Creek Fire
                was reported at about 11:30 a.m. on Thursday, August 1, 2019. The fire was ignited
                by lightning that was part of a thunderstorm that came over the area the night
                before. Due to technical issues, photos are being shared on the Forest Facebook
                page: www.facebook.com/HLCNF. The forest, along with some additional resources, is
                working to completely suppress the fire.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Roberts Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 09:12:49 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 09:12:49 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>33.61 -107.40611111111</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>33.61</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-107.40611111111</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6441/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6441/</guid>
            <description>The Roberts Fire, in the Apache Kid Wilderness in the San Mateo Mountains,
                located on the Magdalena Ranger District, is a lightning caused fire that began July
                13, 2019. The fire is currently burning in Ponderosa Pine, grass, and brush in steep
                terrain with limited access. Road and trail use is not advised in the area due to
                the fire traffic and the proximity of the fire. Smoke will be visible from New
                Mexico 52, New Mexico 107, and U.S. Highway 60 west of Magdalena, NM and I-25 south
                of Socorro, NM as fire behavior increases. The fire size is likely to increase
                throughout the week with district closures likely to be implemented on Forest roads
                and trails.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tincup Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 08:39:13 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 08:39:13 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>43.003888888889 -111.2875</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>43.003888888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.2875</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6489/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6489/</guid>
            <description>The Tincup Fire was discovered on July 30 approximately 30 miles northeast
                of Soda Springs near the Grays Lake Wildlife Refuge Headquarters. The
                lightning-caused fire is approximately .5 acres in size and creeping in dead and
                down fuel with minimal fire activity observed. The fire is slowly spreading towards
                the northeast. The Caribou-Targhee National Forest is aware of several unique values
                in the area including private in-holdings, recreation trails, Hwy 34 and range
                infrastructure. Due to the location of the fire and the observed fire behavior, fire
                officials feel it important to let the Tincup Fire play its natural role in the
                ecosystem. The mixed conifer and aspen ecosystem found in southeast Idaho has
                evolved with and depends on fire. This does not mean the fire will burn without
                human intervention. Active measures will occur to create fuel breaks on forest
                service lands between public and private lands to prevent fire spread onto private
                lands. Should fire activity increase or...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Goose Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:32:35 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:32:35 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>41.937222222222 -114.16583333333</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>41.937222222222</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-114.16583333333</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6503/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6503/</guid>
            <description>This is the final 209, this fire will be called controlled</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>HK Complex (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:25:26 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:25:26 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>45.045277777778 -119.4625</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>45.045277777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-119.4625</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6507/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6507/</guid>
            <description>The HK Complex is a combination of 14 lightning fires that were reported on
                Aug.5, 2019 following a lightning storm on the Forest. The fires are located near
                the Alder Creek Skookum Trailhead, approximately two miles east of Tupper Guard
                Station. The fire is burning in grass, brush and timber. Firefighters and aerial
                resources were promptly dispatched to the fires, however strong evening winds
                produced rapid fire growth, causing some of the fires to grow together and
                increasing the overall fire size to approximately 2,455 acres. A Type 2 Incident
                Management Team took command of the fire at 6 a.m. on Aug. 8, 2019.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Swan Lake Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 20:20:12 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 20:20:12 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>60.630555555556 -150.43777777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>60.630555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-150.43777777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6387/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6387/</guid>
            <description>Swan Lake Fire History On June 5, 2019, the Swan Lake Fire was ignited by
                lightning in a remote area of the Kenai National Wildlife Refuge Wilderness. It was
                reported at 4 to 5 acres, one of 11 fires reported June 5 and 6. It was in the
                Limited Protection zone and put in monitor status.By June 10, the fire had grown to
                over 2,500 acres. A local Type 3 Incident Management Team (IMT) assumed command of
                the fire. The community of Sterling and the Enstar Natural Gas pipeline were
                determined to be values at risk. On June 12, the fire reached the identified MAPs
                and the strategic operations plan was implemented. Two crews were ordered and the
                Type 3 IMT was expanded. By June 16, the fire had grown to over 12,700 acres. Over
                110 personnel were assigned to the fire. A Temporary Flight Restriction (TFR) was
                issued for the fire vicinity to protect aircraft working on the fire. A Type 2 IMT
                was ordered. On June 17, crews began burnout operations along the indirect line east
                of the East Fork...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Granite Gulch Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 18:15:40 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 18:15:40 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>45.178055555556 -117.42694444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>45.178055555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-117.42694444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6498/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6498/</guid>
            <description>OverviewThe Granite Gulch fire was ignited by lightning during a storm that
                rolled through the area on July 14th. It went unnoticed until Sunday July 28th when
                it was reported by hikers. Fire personnel were sent in to monitor and record fire
                behavior, weather, and fuel moisture to aid in modeling the fire spread potential
                over the coming months, the peak of fire season in the Northwest. On July 29th, the
                size was estimated at 25 acres.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cheat Summit Fort Burn Piles (Prescribed Fire)</title>
            <published>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 16:20:04 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 16:20:04 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>38.622222222222 -79.879166666667</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>38.622222222222</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-79.879166666667</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6517/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6517/</guid>
            <description>August 12, 1545: Burning operation were completed at 1545, and the site is
                being monitored. August 12, 1200: At noon Monday, August 12, fire staff is burning
                four wood debris piles on two acres at Cheat Summit Fort in Randolph County. Smoke
                may be visible in the area.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mill Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 11:27:18 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 11:27:18 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.009166666667 -121.46722222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.009166666667</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-121.46722222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6478/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6478/</guid>
            <description>The Mill Fire was reported at 5:36 a.m. on July 30, 2019, on Mill Creek,
                off of the Nacimiento-Ferguson Road and north-west of the Ventana Wilderness. It was
                held at approximately 310 acres and fully contained as of August 12 at 6 pm. A
                Forest Closure Order issued for the Nacimiento Ferguson Road from Highway 1 to the
                Forest Boundary at Fort Hunter Liggett; the Kirk Creek Trail from Highway 1 to Cone
                Peak Road; and the Mill Creek Trail at the junction of Nacimiento Ferguson Road to
                South Coast Ridge Road has been lifted. Cone Peak Road from the junction of
                Nacimiento Ferguson Road to Cone Peak and South Coast Ridge Road from the junction
                of Nacimiento Ferguson Road to Chalk Peak remains closed. There is currently one
                engine crew assigned to the fire. Evacuations: There are currently no evacuations
                orders in effect for the Mill Fire. However, California’s wildfire season is just
                beginning. Please visit https://www.readyforwildfire.org to learn preparedness
                information that will...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Corta Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:32:58 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:32:58 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>40.311944444444 -115.61888888889</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>40.311944444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-115.61888888889</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6501/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6501/</guid>
            <description>The 16,000 acre lightning caused Corta Fire is located approximately 8
                miles southeast of Jiggs,
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>June Lightning 2019 (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 17:49:23 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 17:49:23 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.064444444444 -118.18527777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.064444444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-118.18527777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6396/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6396/</guid>
            <description>Patrol status Kernville, Ca. Update - Lightning Fires: Kern Plateau
                originating June 17th from a thunder storm. The fires are located in the South
                Sierra Wilderness, in extremely steep, rocky terrain, thus proving to be difficult
                to access for personnel. Fires have been dropped to a Type 5 incident and camp at
                Troy Overflow has been wrapped up.Both the Bald and Lost fires are now in patrol
                status. Firefighters did an excellent job of meeting goals, and utilizing MIST
                tactics in the Wilderness.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>San Juan NF Prescribed Fire Program (Prescribed Fire)</title>
            <published>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 16:24:35 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 16:24:35 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>37.278888888889 -107.88222222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>37.278888888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-107.88222222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6288/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6288/</guid>
            <description>The Fall prescribed fire program will be kicking off in mid-August. Stay
                tuned for more
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Museum Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:28:05 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:28:05 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>35.263055555556 -111.63861111111</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>35.263055555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.63861111111</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6450/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6450/</guid>
            <description>The museum fire is 100% contained and in &quot;Patrol Status&quot; with one
                engine
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Verde Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 10:26:44 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 10:26:44 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>33.729166666667 -111.59472222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>33.729166666667</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.59472222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6506/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6506/</guid>
            <description>The area closure for the Verde Fire was lifted August 10 at 7:00am.The
                lightning caused Verde Fire was reported on Saturday, August 3rd after thunderstorms
                passed through the area. The fire is burning on the east side of the Verde River,
                near Black Mesa, approximately two miles northeast of Fort McDowell Reservation
                lands, and four miles east of the community of Rio Verde. The fire is burning in
                grass and brush in a remote area with limited road access for fire
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>North Hills Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 21:40:33 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 21:40:33 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>46.750555555556 -111.95222222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>46.750555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.95222222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6464/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6464/</guid>
            <description>The North Hills Fire is 100% contained and on patrol. A significant
                thundershower occurred over the fire area. There is potential for flash floods and
                debris flow in the burn scar. https://www.lccountymt.gov/des.html Occasional smoke
                and/or dust devils may be visible in the future. The North Hills Fire will continue
                to be
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lick Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 14:34:48 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 14:34:48 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>47.161944444444 -115.89972222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>47.161944444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-115.89972222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6491/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6491/</guid>
            <description>The Lick Creek Fire was discovered on August 2 at 50 acres. The fire is
                located in the Lick Creek drainage, 6 miles SW from Avery, Idaho. With more accurate
                mapping, the fire has been determined at 200 acres, burning primarily on
                Potlatch-Deltic Corporation Land at around 90% and partially on Forest Service Land
                10%. The fire is burning in heavy logging slash and timber. Priority on the fire is
                to protect the safety of fire personnel and human life followed by the protection of
                private property, reduce impacts to Potlatch-Deltic grounds and confine fire to the
                existing box that was created by retardant drops. Full suppression tactics will be
                used to safely, effectively and efficiently reduce the spread of the fire. As of
                August 10, 2019 the fire is 100% contained and expected to have minimal creeping and
                smoldering within the fire parameter. The North Idaho Type 3 Team plans to transfer
                back command to the District on August 11, 2019. Local resources plan to continue to
                patrol,...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Springs Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:08:59 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:08:59 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>38.948888888889 -117.72833333333</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>38.948888888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-117.72833333333</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6508/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6508/</guid>
            <description>The Green Springs Fire is burning in pinyon and juniper in the Green
                Springs area of the Paradise Range. It is located east of Gabbs, Nevada and north of
                Nevada State Route 841.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IPNF Backcountry Prescribed Fire 2019 (Prescribed Fire)</title>
            <published>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 13:44:25 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 13:44:25 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>47.841666666667 -116.25138888889</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>47.841666666667</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-116.25138888889</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6476/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6476/</guid>
            <description>&amp;#183;At this time there are no active prescribed fire operations.
                Information will be clearly posted when ignitions occur. Prescribed burning is part
                of the USDA Forest Service natural resources management program. Areas described as
                Backcountry Managements Areas in the Idaho Panhandle National Forests (IPNF) Land
                Management Plan (Forest Plan) need treated in order to reduce hazardous fuels,
                improve wildlife habitat, and to establish and maintain a resilient forest
                structure. Fire serves as one of the best management activities in the backcountry.
                Approximately 92 percent of Backcountry Management Areas are within Inventoried
                Roadless Areas, which are not suitable for timber harvest, making prescribed fire
                the best tool to improve forest conditions. Prescribed fire objectives are more
                likely to be achieved with more summer-like conditions within these high elevation
                areas, especially during a moderate fire season. Please see map for areas of
                potential implementation areas. More...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Barren Hill Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 19:00:11 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 19:00:11 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>46.236944444444 -114.98277777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>46.236944444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-114.98277777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6468/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6468/</guid>
            <description>The Moose Creek Ranger District of the Nez Perce-Clearwater National
                Forests is managing the lightning-caused Barren Hill Fire for wilderness and
                resource objectives. Reported at 12:50 on July 1, the fire is located approximately
                17 miles SW of the Powell Ranger Station in the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness Area.
                The fire does not pose a risk to communities or other values such as timber
                resources or human improvements. Fire behavior over the month has varied greatly.
                Some days a low-intensity fire slowly burned on the forest floor with other days
                seeing much greater activity including significant surface fire, single and group
                tree torching and some short uphill runs. All aspects have seen some fire with
                different responses due to the variances in vegetation and fuel moistures.Trail
                closures are in effect for the area, including the Barren Hill, Barren Creek,
                Wounded Doe Licks, North Moose and the North Fork Moose trails. See the “Closures”
                section on the top of the page. It is...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Wagon Mountain Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:54:27 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:54:27 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>46.658888888889 -114.56333333333</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>46.658888888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-114.56333333333</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6505/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6505/</guid>
            <description>Wagon Mountain Fire, Missoula Ranger District Location: Located on top of
                Wagon Mountain, approximately 2 miles northeast of Lolo Pass Visitor Center and east
                of Highway 12. Not to be confused with the Wagon Mountain Road between Graves Creek
                and Fish Creek Roads on the west side of Highway 12. Status: The Wagon Mountain Fire
                was detected on Aug. 5, 2019 at approximately 2:30 p.m. by aircraft responding to
                the West Fork Lolo 2 Fire. The fire is burning in a previously logged area in new
                regeneration and also in mature spruce and mixed conifer. The fire is currently
                staffed as a Type 4 incident. Containment: 100% reached on 8/8/19 at 6:30 p.m.
                Structures or other values at risk: None at this time. No evacuations are in effect
                at this time.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Woodbury Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:36:32 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:36:32 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>33.409444444444 -111.19916666667</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>33.409444444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.19916666667</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6382/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6382/</guid>
            <description>The Woodbury is now 100% controlled. State Route 88 Closure: Because of the
                potential for severe flooding from areas burned in the Woodbury Fire, a 7-mile,
                unpaved section of State Route 88 (Apache Trail) will remain closed from an area
                several miles east of Tortilla Flat to just west of the Apache Lake marina turnoff
                while the Arizona Department of Transportation continues assessing conditions. All
                inquiries in regards to the closure on State Route 88 (Apache Trail Historic Road)
                should be directed to ADOT. You can submit questions to ADOT by online form or phone
                by visiting https://azdot.gov/contact. Tortilla Flat business remain open.
                Additional information regarding the highway closure can be found at:
                https://azdot.gov/media/News/news-release/2019/07/29/seven-mile-stretch-of-sr-88-remains-closed-due-to-flooding-risk
                Forest Closure: For the purposes of public safety, the forest closure extends beyond
                the fire perimeter. The forest closure includes a portion of the Arizona Trail...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ghost Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 08:12:26 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 08:12:26 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>33.661944444444 -108.41055555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>33.661944444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-108.41055555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6499/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6499/</guid>
            <description>The lightning-caused Ghost Fire, reported on Saturday, August 3 is
                approximately 40 acres, burning on National Forest System lands in Catron County,
                NM. It is burning in ponderosa pine pinyon juniper, oak, and grass approximately 3
                miles east of Collins Park. The crew and two engines plan to keep the fire south of
                the Bursum Road in Y Canyon, east of FR 4047U, and north of FR 4047Z. The fire is
                visible from Elk Springs Subdivision and NM Highway 12 as crews burn out in advance
                of the fire. The Fire is exhibiting moderate to low fire effects. This particular
                area is drier than most of the surrounding area, but is anticipated to receive rain
                with the current forecast.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Bear Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 08:11:14 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 08:11:14 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>33.576388888889 -107.98444444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>33.576388888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-107.98444444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6434/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6434/</guid>
            <description>The lightning-caused Bear Fire is approximately 1,350 acres, burning on
                National Forest System lands in the Black Range Ranger District. This fire is
                approximately 25 miles northwest of Winston, NM. Minimal fire activity is occurring
                and is moderated by occasional precipitation.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Adobe Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 08:10:20 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 08:10:20 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>33.537777777778 -107.87555555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>33.537777777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-107.87555555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6500/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6500/</guid>
            <description>The lightning-caused Adobe Fire, reported Saturday, August 3, is
                approximately 125 acres, burning on National Forest System lands, Sierra County, NM.
                This fire lies just east of the private property, Los Adobe Ranch; and three miles
                south of an El Paso Electric powerline. It is burning in grass and ponderosa pine.
                This fire is visible from Winston, NM. With predicted weather, values, fire growth
                potential a decision has been made to manage this fire and allow fire to play its
                natural role on the landscape.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lick Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 16:38:48 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 16:38:48 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>44.850833333333 -107.69</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>44.850833333333</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-107.69</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6479/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6479/</guid>
            <description>On the evening of July 30th, firefighters were looking for two reported
                fires in northern portion of the Bighorn National Forest. It was determined that
                there is likely only one fire, named the Lick Creek fire. This fire is located
                approximately one mile down Forest Trail 076, accessed by Forest Road 147, off of
                the Dayton Gulch Road (Forest Road 15). It is described as Township 56N, R 90 W,
                Section 9. It is currently 4 acres in size, burning in heavy timber fuels.
                Approximately 15 firefighters using All Terrain Vehicles and one helicopter from the
                Wyoming State Forestry arrived on the fire this morning to begin suppression actions
                of fireline construction and water drops. An additional 10 firefighters have been
                ordered to help secure the fire. Weather will remain hot and dry, and while the fire
                danger indeces are currently Moderate, the fire has potential to grow with passing
                thunderstorm winds that could hit the fire. The public should remain out of the fire
                area. Forest Road 147...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Museum Fire BAER Info (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title>
            <published>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 12:18:48 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 12:18:48 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>35.257777777778 -111.64305555556</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>35.257777777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.64305555556</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6482/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6482/</guid>
            <description>A Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team has been established to begin
                burned area surveys of the Museum Fire. BAER team assessments are rapid evaluations
                of post-fire conditions of the burned landscape to determine the level of risk from
                potential flooding and debris flow to values on National Forest System lands such as
                human life, safety, property, and critical natural and cultural resources. If
                unacceptable risks are found the team recommends appropriate and effective emergency
                stabilization measures to reduce the risks to National Forest lands and values. BAER
                teams conduct field surveys and use science-based models to rapidly evaluate and
                assess the burned area. The BAER program is designed to identify and manage
                potential risks to resources on NFS lands and reduce these threats through
                appropriate emergency measures to protect human life and safety, property, and
                critical natural or cultural resources. BAER is an emergency program for
                stabilization work that involves...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Newman Fire BAER Info (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title>
            <published>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 18:32:11 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 18:32:11 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>35.0225 -111.525</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>35.0225</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.525</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6483/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6483/</guid>
            <description>A Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team has been established to begin
                burned area surveys of the Museum Fire. BAER team assessments are rapid evaluations
                of post-fire conditions of the burned landscape to determine the level of risk from
                potential flooding and debris flow to values on National Forest System (NFS) lands
                such as human life, safety, property, and critical natural and cultural resources.
                If unacceptable risks are found the team recommends appropriate and effective
                emergency stabilization measures to reduce the risks to National Forest lands and
                values. BAER teams conduct field surveys and use science-based models to rapidly
                evaluate and assess the burned area. The BAER program is designed to identify and
                manage potential risks to resources on NFS lands and reduce these threats through
                appropriate emergency measures to protect human life and safety, property, and
                critical natural or cultural resources. BAER is an emergency program for
                stabilization work that...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Woodbury Fire - BAER (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title>
            <published>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 16:47:03 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 16:47:03 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>33.442777777778 -111.16583333333</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>33.442777777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-111.16583333333</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6405/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6405/</guid>
            <description>Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) teams have been established to begin
                burned area surveys of the wildfires that recently burned on federal lands of the
                U.S. Forest Service - Southwestern Region. BAER team surveys are rapid assessments
                of the burned areas that evaluate post-fire conditions of the burned watersheds and
                determine the potential for increased post-fire flooding, sediment flows, and
                rockslides. BAER teams typically consist of scientists and specialists including
                hydrologists, geologists, soil scientists, road engineers, botanists, wildlife and
                fisheries biologists, archaeologists, recreation and trails specialists, and
                geographic information specialists, from federal and state agencies. BAER teams work
                together during the burned area surveys, field data analysis and modeling phase, to
                present findings along with recommended BAER treatments to the Forest Supervisor.
                BAER teams analyze the data they collect during the surveys, to produce a “Soil Burn
                Severity”...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Canyon Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 08:03:56 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 08:03:56 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>44.250555555556 -115.2275</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>44.250555555556</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-115.2275</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6438/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6438/</guid>
            <description>Canyon Fire 100 percent containment on August 2, 2019With 88 percent
                containment of the 326 acre Canyon Fire, firefighters have made significant progress
                toward containment Aug. 2, 2019. Crews will continue to secure, patrol and monitor
                lines for flare ups along all sides and particularly along the northern flank near
                the West Fork of Canyon Creek. Demobilization is occurring sending many of the
                resources to other fires or back to their home units. The fire suppression repair
                plan, to mitigate any adverse impacts resulting from fire suppression activities,
                has been implemented. WEATHER: A smattering of lightning and spotty rain occurred
                during the arrival of a dry cold front Tuesday evening. Aerial detection patrols
                have been ordered to look for new ignitions. Resources will respond to any new fires
                or hold overs that flare up in the next few days. The next frontal system is
                predicted to arrive over southern Idaho, Friday. RESOURCES: Currently there are 34
                personnel on the fire...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Sherman Prescribed Burn (Prescribed Fire)</title>
            <published>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 15:32:07 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 15:32:07 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.582777777778 -118.75416666667</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.582777777778</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-118.75416666667</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6245/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6245/</guid>
            <description>Fire staff completed ignitions on the last segment of the Sherman
                Prescribed Burn on Thursday, July 11th, for a total of 245 acres treated. With
                ignitions complete, firefighters will continue to patrol the area as vegetation
                inside the unit burns down. Access to the General Sherman Tree remains open from the
                Sherman Tree parking lots.The Sherman Prescribed Burn is located in the Giant Forest
                area of Sequoia National Park, approximately one half mile northeast of the Giant
                Forest Museum. Visitors driving or hiking near the area may see smoke and/or areas
                of active flame, and are asked to exercise caution, stay on trails, and observe
                signs and directions from park staff. Some trails, including the Congress Trail,
                have been reopened. Other trails remain closed due to lingering fire activity and
                other hazards. Closures are clearly flagged. Open trails do not necessarily mean
                that the area is cold. Visitors on these trails are likely to encounter smoke,
                smoldering, or pockets of active...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Graham Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 11:47:14 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 11:47:14 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>47.456666666667 -117.68222222222</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>47.456666666667</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-117.68222222222</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6459/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6459/</guid>
            <description>The Graham fire was one of four fires that started July 24, 2019, southwest
                of Cheney, WA. Firefighters from local, state and federal agencies responded and
                worked effectively to suppress the fires. Northeast Washington Interagency Incident
                Management Team 2 was ordered to help manage the Graham Fire and three smaller fires
                in the area. The team is currently assisting the local jurisdictions with the
                Graham, Badger, Lake Badger and Grogan
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nugget Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:22:47 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:22:47 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>64.873888888889 -146.55527777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>64.873888888889</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-146.55527777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6401/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6401/</guid>
            <description>The lightning-caused Nugget Creek Fire started on June 21, 2019
                approximately 35 miles east of Fairbanks in the area of 30 Mile Chena Hot Springs
                Road in the Chena River State Recreation Area. Air attack responded and reported a
                150-acre burning in black spruce approximately 2 miles from Chena Hot Springs Road
                on the south side of the river. The fire plotted in a Limited protection area near
                the South Fork Chena River. No resources were threatened and the fire was placed in
                monitor
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Shovel Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 16:19:53 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 16:19:53 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>64.986944444444 -148.41527777778</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>64.986944444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-148.41527777778</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6400/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6400/</guid>
            <description>The Shovel Creek Fire (#319) was started by lightning on June 21 and is
                located 3 miles north of Murphy Dome, about 20 miles northwest of Fairbanks.
                Depending on weather conditions, smoke from this fire may drift into the Fairbanks
                and surrounding areas in the coming weeks. The fire started in a Full Protection
                Area and the Division of Forestry ordered water-scooping aircraft, air retardant
                tankers and smokejumpers for initial attack. Burning in continuous black spruce, the
                fire grew quickly and was estimated to be 300 acres on the first evening. The
                Northern Rockies Team 6, led by Incident Commander Bob Fry, assumed command of the
                incident on July 15 at 6pm. The objectives for the incident include:Hold the fire
                perimeter, mop up to the extent necessary to reduce the likelihood of escape based
                on firefighter experience, terrain, fuel type, and both current and expected fire
                behavior and weather in the following locations:• Chatanika River south to Murphy
                Dome through the Hard Luck...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Francisquito Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 10:47:40 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 10:47:40 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>36.449444444444 -106.20694444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>36.449444444444</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-106.20694444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6444/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6444/</guid>
            <description>The Francisquito Fire was detected on July 13th on the El Rito Ranger
                District of the Carson National Forest, approximately 7 miles north of the community
                of El Rito. The fire is creeping with low to moderate fire behavior and is not a
                threat to any values at risk. Firefighters will use ignitions to continue to treat
                this area.Access to the fire is difficult so firefighters have scouted the area for
                opportunities to find roads or other natural barriers to use to confine the fire to
                a certain area. The forest just north of these fires already burned in 2018 as part
                of the Alamosa Prescribed Fire which will provide an opportunity to limit fire
                spread. After taking into consideration the fire’s location, the fuels it is burning
                in, considerable green-up in the forest, and current and predicted precipitation,
                the Carson National Forest decided to manage these fires to achieve multiple
                resource benefits. The forest’s first priority is always firefighter and public
                safety. Allowing the...
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Montana Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title>
            <published>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:37:07 -05:00</published>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:37:07 -05:00</pubDate>
            <georss:point>62.1225 -149.98694444444</georss:point>
            <geo:lat>62.1225</geo:lat>
            <geo:long>-149.98694444444</geo:long>
            <link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6424/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6424/</guid>
            <description>The Montana Creek Fire started at 3:00 P.M. on 7-3-2019. Cause of fire is
                under investigation. The fire is located 2 ½ miles east of the Parks Highway at Mile
                98, south of the Talkeetna Cutoff.
            </description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>